Louise Pike

Software Engineer

https://louise-pike.netlify.app/

https://github.com/stars/louisep1/lists/portfolio

Tokyo, Japan

louisepike@live.co.uk https://www.linkedin.com/in/louise-pike-82b2b9247/

Projects

Clean Hotels | React, MySQL, Sass

Using React and Sass/SCSS in the frontend and MySQL, Express and Node.js in the backend, users can browse the page of this small chain of local hotels and reserve a room today. https://clean-hotels.onrender.com

Event Ticket Page | Node.js, Mongoose, Bootstrap

Using React with Bootstrap styling in the frontend and MongoDB, Mongoose and Express in the backend, this full stack app allows users to buy and sell tickets to their favourite events. https://event-ticket-page.onrender.com/

Social Networking App | DaisyUI, Tailwind, React

The Social Network App is a mobile-first messaging page, built with React, Tailwind CSS and DaisyUI in the frontend, inspired by popular modern-day messaging services and designed for optimum use on a mobile device. Users can search for friends by email address and send messages.

https://social-network-app.onrender.com/

Work Experience

Software Engineer | Pyxos Corp

Japan

December 2022 to present

- Vue.js, Vuex, JavaScript/TypeScript, Sass/SCSS, HTML, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Socket.io, Jest, Google Cloud Platform
- Full stack online, cloud-based clinical web application manage patient records calculate payments, insurance and
 performance statistics make reservations in realtime.
- Overseeing the whole process from design, creation, testing, production and beyond.
- Implementing new features, fixing bugs, actively improving user experience, responding to client requests, writing unit tests, performing code reviews and testing.
- Agile software development, kanban (trello)

Summary

Highly-motivated software engineer, specialising in full stack web development. As a developer, I enjoy the challenge of continually learning and solving problems and find great fulfillment in seeing code work successfully and in building new and inovative features.

Tech stack / Skills

Frontend:

JavaScript TypeScript CSS HTML Vue.js Vuex React React Router Redux Redux Toolkit Jest Sass/SCSS Bootstrap Tailwind CSS Daisy UI Axios

Backend:

Node.js Express MySQL SQL Sequelize NoSQL MongoDB Mongoose JSON Web Token Bcrypt Socket.io

Additional tools/skills:

GitHub/GitHub Desktop Postman Google Cloud Platform (GCP) HeidiSQL MySQL Workbench XAMPP phpMyAdmin MongoDB Compass Firebase/Firestore PayPal Sandbox Heroku Render Agile development Kanban

(Self-studied between April 2021 - December 2022)

Past Work Experience

Educator | Yaruki Switch Group

July 2019 to July 2022 (3 years)

- Teaching children with very little English experience and exposure.
- Focus on active language production.
- · Adept at working with clients (students) directly, face-to-face, considering their needs, goals and requirements.
- Worked within a diverse team of Japanese and international staff.

Nursery Manager | Tinysaurus Nurseries

February 2018 to March 2019 (1 year)

- Started as a Trainee Manager, then Assistant Manager, then Nursery Manager
- · Leadership of staff and overseeing tasks, officer of health and safety, delivering training, recruitment, marketing, ensuring customer satisfaction, dealing with complains and issues.

Receptionist | Kicks Martial Arts Center

January 2016 to July 2019 (3½ years)

- Part-time work as a receptionist at a local martial arts centre.
- Teamwork and communication were essential to this smaller, family-run business.

Activities Coordinator | Lyndhurst Rest Homes

August 2016 to March 2017 (½ year)

• Organised activities for elderly residents in a care home. (Part-time)

Education History



CELTA (Cambridge English Level 5 Certificate in Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages) | St Giles, Brighton

April - May 2019 Grade A Pass



MA International Education and Development | University of Sussex

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017 Merit

BA Childhood and Youth | **University of Sussex**

Sept 2013 - July 2016 First Class Honours

Languages

English Native

Japanese Conversational

Japan

Q UK

Passions

Dance Scuba diving Travel Outdoors Walking Learning